Um, what we did is we took an array with
arrays in it and made it into an array
with objects in it. And we could have
done the reverse. We could have made an
object with arrays in it. And we can
stack these as deep as we want. We could
put objects with arrays that have
objects in them um all inside of each
other. Um, naturally that's the way most
of the internet communicates. Um,
stacking arrays and objects together is
a structured form of storing data. And
we call this form JSON or which stands
for JavaScript object notation. And you
can do some pretty cool things with it.
Um that is the way that the vast
majority of websites talk to each other
is they send each other information
packaged up in this JSON format or in
other words strings sorry objects and
arrays inside of each other.
Well
I'm going to show you one of the cool
ways to apply that. So, if you are on a
Mac, hit commandshiftp. If you are on a
Windows, hit control shiftp. That will
pop up this top tab right here. And I
want you to type in the word snippets.
And I need to move this bar so I can
actually see what I'm doing. Okay. And I
want you to click um configure snippets.
Then what I want you to do is I want you
to type JS
and click on JavaScript.
What this allows you to do is it allows
you to write JSON, which will let you
use keyboard shortcuts to type something
short and have it prefill in your code.
So, if I come back over to script.js,
for example, if I type console, um, you
can see it pops up here and I can hit
tab and it will autocomplete for me.
Well, wouldn't it be nice if we could
write our own? Well, we can. All we have
to do is follow JSON syntax. So JSON has
an object here and in that object we
need to put keys and values or
definitions and the things that they're
storing. Um if we're thinking of our
dictionary example. So for example maybe
it takes me forever to write a function.
So I'm going to type the word um create
function.
Then I'm going to put a colon and curly
braces. So this here
is um information about
the shortcut I'm creating. And then
inside of that object, we need to keep
create a key called prefix. Okay, this
is what we want to type to quickly get
um for our message to pop up. So when we
start typing console and hit tab, it
writes the full word console. So what is
the keyboard shortcut you want to type?
Well, for me, for a function, it' be
nice if I could type f u n c.
Great. Then it says, what code do you
want me to replace that shortcut with?
Well, this can actually take an array,
and each item in that array is a line of
code, and then they'll be entered onto
new lines. So for example, I could say I
want to write the word fun um const
um my function
and I want to set it equal to opening
parenthesis
and then an arrow and then an opening
curly brace. Then I'm going to put a
comma. Then I'm going to say on the next
line I want you to put the keyword
return. And then on the next line, I
want you to put a closing curly brace.
So what this does is it effectively
writes us a function with all of those
on different lines. It loops through
this array, grabs information out of it,
and puts it onto your VS Code page. Um,
and then I'm going to put a comma after
this body attribute, which is storing
this array. And I'm going to add one
last attribute, which is called
description. This describes what my
keyboard shortcut does. And I'll say
shortcut to write a function.
When we save this, we can come over here
to script.js. We said when we type f, we
want it to autopop populate. So if I
type f c and hit tab, boom, it put in
all that code that I just asked for.
Well, this is great. But every time we
call it, our variable is going to be
named my function. Also, wouldn't it be
nice if we could fill in some
parameters? Also, maybe we don't always
want to return and it'd be nice if we
could put some stuff into this function.
So, now what I want to show you is how
you can edit what we just did so that
it'll automatically put your cursor in
those locations and you can hit tab. So,
when I create a function, I want to say
const and where I have my function, I
actually
just want the user to type something.
And then here in these parentheses is
the next place they're want to want to
type something. So I'm going to type
dollar sign two. And what it does is
it'll put the user's cursor in those
locations when they type this. And so
instead of putting return, I'm going to
put dollar sign 3. And then um where you
want the final position to be is where
you put dollar sign zero.
So, I'm going to save this and I'm going
to come over here to script.js and I'm
going to call my um keyboard shortcut
again. So, I'll type f and c, hit tab.
Notice it put my cursor here. I can call
this my function. Then hit tab. Then it
automatically put my cursor in the next
position I told it I wanted to. So, I
could say num one and then num two and
then hit tab. And then it put my cursor
into the function itself. And then I can
say return num one plus num two. And
then I'll hit tab and it puts my cursor
at the end of the function which is very
very cool. Um the last thing I wanted to
show you is you can put a cursor in
multiple places at the same time. So for
example, if I type another dollar sign
one, what it'll do is it'll put my
cursor both here and here. So, if I save
this and I come over here and I type
my keyboard shortcut, notice my cursor
is now in two places. And this can make
it a lot faster to write code. If you
have code that you're repeating over and
over, for example, maybe defining a
function, you can take advantage of
objects
with keys that are holding another
object with a key that's holding an
array. And so you can nest objects and
arrays together to make your VS Code do
some really cool